Sergio Arturo Pérez

Systems Engineer with five years of experience in managing and developing automation and process optimization projects in various sectors. I have worked with clients in Colombia, Mexico, Chile and EEUU, using agile development methodologies such as SCRUM and DevOps, and development frameworks in UiPath and Automation Anywhere. My expertise in process optimization, and automation has delivered significant improvements in operational efficiency and cost savings for clients.

EXPERIENCE

Accelirate - Automation Engineer

February 2023

Responsible for designing and implementing new process requirements. Experienced in developing bots that integrate APIs, OCR, and various database engines to achieve complete process automation. Proficient in using Power Automate, UiPath, Azure, Jira, and other development tools to deliver successful projects.

Globant - Ssr Adv Developer RPA

August 2022 - January 2023

I design, develop, and architect bots with a focus on integrating and continuously distributing automations. I have led efforts to standardize frameworks, develop documentation, and define guidelines that promote best practices in RPA project development and management. Additionally, I review deliverable code to ensure that the final product meets high-quality standards.

Wipro Limited - Senior Developer RPA

November 2019 – April 2022

I worked as an RPA Developer on multiple projects across Colombia, Mexico, and Chile, spanning a range of industries including banking, food, textiles, and others. My experience includes developing solutions in UiPath and Automation Anywhere, utilizing programming languages such as Python, C#, and VB. As a technical leader, I supported project management and contributed to pre-sales and proof-of-concept development. I focused on creating architectures that optimize RPA processes and applications, with a goal of maximizing return on investment. Additionally, I successfully migrated bots from Automation Anywhere version 11 to A360 version.

Tata Consultancy Services - *Developer RPA*

July 2019 – November 2019

As an RPA Developer and Cell Leader in a telecommunications project involving over 30 automated processes, I was responsible for migrating robots (mostly unattended) across development environments, quality assurance, and production using Automation Anywhere

Control Room tool. I also ensured the quality, testing, and adherence to best practices of solutions produced by other development cells. Additionally, I provided support in the architecture and development of robots using Automation Anywhere.

PwC Colombia - Consultant

June 2018 - July 2019

My role involved managing technology consulting projects, where I also served as a technical leader in some of the projects. I developed over 20 attended and unattended robots across various sectors, including Service Centers, Automotive, Food, Mines, and Energy, using the UiPath tool and applying the best programming practices and RPA advancements.

Education	Systems Engineer	
	Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas	
	2013 - 2019	
Languages	Spanish Native	10/10
	English B2	7/10
Skills	Automation Anywhere	10/10
		40/40
	UiPath	10/10
	Power Automate	7/10
	Rocketbot	7/10
	SQL	9/10
	Java / VB / C#	6/10
Tools	GitHub , Trello, Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps	
Certifications	Automation Anywhere Master (A360) y (V11.0) April 2021 UiPath RPA Developer Advanced March 2019 Bot Builder Rocketbot Expert Level 1 March 2022 Platzi	